I use clot more than any other AI but
even I dismiss Clark as just for
developers and I was wrong after using
myself I am completely so and this is
too powerful to ignore if you want to
use AI to build system and do work for
you end to end not just chatting and
copy pasting so in this video I'll share
how to get started with cloud code even
if you don't use for coding and most
importantly how to use it to build an AI
work team and system that you can
actually use. Let's go.
So why claw code is even needed if claw
is already so powerful. So most people
use cloud projects with custom
instructions to turn claw into AI
agents. But they are silo. You end up
copy and pasting between them. You are
the coordinator. But with cloud code is
different. So these cloud agents share
the same workspace access to the same
context file. They can talk to each
other and hands up work automatically
each with their own token context window
and claude now becomes the team lead.
You give the direction they execute
together and that is what we are
building today. So each of these cloud
code agents you create needs at least
three core components all defined in one
single markdown file. the role and
responsibilities, the knowledge like
workflow details, reusable clot agent
skills, the MCP tools that they have
access to. For this demo, we'll be
building a five agent work and claude,
our main agent will add as our team lead
to coordinate between these agent. A
bonus tip is when designing your AI
teammate, give them specific and
non-over overlapping roles to minimize
the potential conflicts. Now, to get
started with clark code, there are four
main ways to access it. First, the local
terminal. This is the raw method and
will give you the best experience.
Luckily, Anthroporic just launched a
native installer. So, which makes it
really easy to install. I'll put the
official link below. And second, ID
extension. So, you can add CL code to ID
like VS Code or Kursa and let you run
the CL code and see the project file
structure side by side. Third, the cloud
web app where you can click the code tab
and run the CL code in the cloud, but it
requires you linking to a GitHub
repository. and fourth, cloud desktop
app which has cloud code built-in and
this is what we'll be using today. Now,
whatever way you choose, I still highly
recommend installing cloud code through
the terminal first because the terminal
gives you the most complete experience.
All commands and features work fully
since we're running Clark locally. So,
the first thing is to set up a local
project folder. So, think of it like a
dedicated workspace for Clark. So, let's
say I run a marketing agency and I'm
setting up the TIM system. So let's
create a folder called marketing team
and then I highly recommend to include
all useful business context about this
agency brand. Then access code using
whatever method that you choose. So for
our case we will use cloud desktop
application. So navigate to Clark pick
local as the environment and then pick
the folder we just create. Now before we
even create any agents the very first
step is to initiate this project by
creating a cloth.md file. So this is
just like a project system prompt. It
gives all the important context to cla
about what it should know. So ask claw
to read the business context file and
create a cloth.md file and to build the
necessary folder structure. So
immediately cloth has created all the
folders for this agency brand. And we
can even open up an ID to doublech
checkck all the folders and the cloth
empty file. All right. Now let's build
our first teammate the content
strategies. So this is the simplest
version. No clock scales, no MCP tools,
just the basic context file. A key
features of clock code is the slash
command. So you can type slash to
trigger these built-in shortcuts. And
there are lots of them and most of them
are really for coding purpose. So I
won't go through them one by one today.
But for agent creation, we need the CLI
terminal because the Asian commands is
not fully supported in a chat interface
yet. So first type claw just to initiate
a session. So this way you can trigger
the terminal and don't be scared.
Basically this is just a raw sections
for cloud code and a chat interface is
just like a wpper. Now type / agents to
trigger the building cloth agent
configuration. Then select create new
agent. Pick project level agent as this
agents is for this project only. Then
pick generate with clot. So here you can
describe what this agent will do. So in
our case, this is a content strategist
agent that will do web search and
prepare content research documents in MD
files. Then select the tools default
clock model color for this agent to use.
And now we're done. We have create our
first clot agents for this work team.
And whenever you want to call this
agent, just tag this agent name in any
cloud code session. So we can double
check using the VS code IDE and you will
see from the folder it has created the
agent under the agents folder. So
basically it's just an empty file
containing the system prompt defining
the role and the capabilities for this
agent and you can always change it since
this agent will also use different
strategy templates. We can also ask it
to create all the necessary templates
that this agent will use. And this is
the power of CL code because it not only
created files for you but also put it in
the right folder according to this team
system structure. So no more copy and
paste. Immediately these templates have
been created under the template folder
like the campaign plan content brief
content strategy template. So they are
really detailed and this is fantastic.
Now to use this agent in a chat
interface just tag this agent or just
use plain language to specify the agent
name and ask it to research the latest
SEO challenges and prepare a content
brief. So you will see it will trigger
different web searches and also reading
the content brief template file that it
just create and then after a few minutes
the content brief is ready and this is
super comprehensive and the agent has
followed everything stated in the
template. So do not just create an
agent. Always give it context,
templates, resource, standard rules to
follow. So it will always produce
quality output like this. Now that you
have seen how easy it is to build
content agents with AI, here is the
catch. Consumers have strong opinions
about AI generated content. If you want
to understand what they actually think
and how to implement AI without losing
their trust, this free report from
HubSpot and Survey Monkey, how brands
are earning loyalty in an automated
world covers exactly that in detail. You
can find the link below based on the
data from over 15,000 consumers
globally. Only 24% of consumers actually
like seeing AI in their emails, ads, or
customer support. And 84% want to know
when brands are using AI. That is a
trust gap you need to close. And what I
also found valuable is a section about
operational best practices for staying
authentic with AI. It gives you five
actionable strategies to implement AI
without losing the human connection.
Download this for free in the
description. And thank you HubSpot and
Survey Monkey for sponsoring this video.
All right, let's create our second
agent, a presentation specialist. And
this time, let's also add clock agent
skills. So skills are just like a
reusable instruction manual that tells
claw how to execute your task and
particularly for this agent we'll use
the official document creation skills.
So enthrop provide a list of official
skills but they are not pre-built inside
clock. So you can go to this official
skills GitHub repository and the easiest
and reliable way is to use the building
plug-in command inside clock. So type
/plugin and register the official skill
repository and then install the document
skills and also I recommend to install
the example skills to enable all other
official skills as well. Then we can use
this prompt to double confirm these
skills are successfully made available
inside cloud code. Now again use the
embedded terminal inside cloud desktop
and use the agent configuration mode to
create these presentation specialist
agent. This agent will transform all the
data into pawn slide decks. Note I also
specify the brand color palettes here.
So this agent will always follow these
color tone when generating the slides.
Then quickly we have our second agent
builds. So let's say we have this
performing data set inside this data
folder. Then we can just tag this agent
name and then ask it to create a
presentation deck for this file under
our folder. And if you're using the
terminal, you can just simply tag the
file path which will be much easier. Now
it triggers the document creation skills
that we have in store and out of film it
create a performance report presentation
for us with 10 slides. So it is quite
decent and is using the color scheme
that we have defined with the color box
charts graphs for storytelling. Although
it's not using very sophisticated
graphics, it's definitely ready to
present and with minimal adjustment. And
so perhaps maybe you have different data
sets, documents, reports. You don't even
need to upload them. You can just put
them inside a folder and then let claw
to scan and load them and call this
agent to build the deck for you. All
right, our third agent which is a data
analyst. So this time we'll be adding
MCP tools. So MCP less clock connect to
external system and retrieve live data
or context and this is where your AI
team become truly powerful. So first we
need to install all the necessary MCB
server and make them available on cloud
code. So if you have been using cloud
desktop you probably already have a list
of MCB servers connected. So the easiest
way is to input them through the local
terminal. So we need to use the
computer's local terminal is because the
embedded one in the clock desktop does
not support this import command. So open
the terminal application. So navigate to
our project folder path using this cd
command. Then use this command mcp at
from clot desktop to import the mcp
servers that you want. So in this case I
have import three mcp servers. Notion
hrefs j4. notes depending on the MCP
server that you install some of them
might require further authentication
before you can use them on cloud code
and to confirm it's already installed go
back to cloud desktop open the terminal
type /mcp and we can see all the three
MCP servers are available now repeat the
same process to build this data analyst
agent with the agent command so this
agent will connect to J4 through the MCP
tool and create parnish interactive HTML
dashboard and again we will use the same
brand color palettes to keep everything
on brand and then now we have three
agents in a team. So let's test this
agent to analyze our website performance
and build a dashboard. So it's now
calling the J4 MCB server to retrieve
the data and quickly it has built us a
dashboard with the photo path. So it is
in the same brand color we have
specified with the executive summary,
key metrics boxes, interactive charts,
trend lines and this is what club really
excels at about strategic storytelling
and insights. Then we can even export
this directly as a PDF file which is
ready to send out to the team for quick
sharing. Now let's level up further. So
we'll create custom skills that make our
agents even more brand specific. And
then we'll build a fourth agent, a
social media specialist who will use
these custom skills. So let's create a
custom skills called branded social
visuals which will be used for creating
branded social graphics. So upload some
visual example for cloth and then ask it
to read the official canvas design
skills and extend it for visual
creations with the specified brand color
layout style for this agency brand. So
now it triggers the official skills
creator we have enabled and studies the
canvas design skills and then extends it
and create a new custom skills following
the official structure. And from the ID
explorer we can also see a new skill MD
file is generated. And so using this
same method, we can create a few more
custom skills perhaps like a keyword
research skills that we call the HF's
MCP and LLM optimized the blog writer
skills that generate AI search friendly
blog and a custom brand voice skills. So
if you want to learn how to build these
custom skills, go check out this video.
So let's see this in action with the
social media specialist agent which will
use this custom skills and a notion MCP.
So we can give it some topic ideas and
ask it to drop the post copy with
visuals and schedule them on our notion
calendar. So it is now calling the
branded social visual skill we just
create for visual creation and then
calls the notion MCP to upload all the
post details to our calendar. And now
all the visuals have been created under
this folder. Although these visuals are
not that fancy, it's also not cloth
strain, but definitely you can see
everything is on brand using the brand
color pallets and with the brand test
logo. So these workflow automation is
100% working. And you can always let
claw use all the image generation model
perhaps Gemini Nano Banana for more
stunning visual images. And claw also
successfully schedule all these posts on
the notion content calendar following
our posting schedule with the platform
details, posting status, postcopy,
hashtag. So this is what make clock so
powerful. Everything can be done like in
30 minutes. Now we have built our AI
team. Four agents you have seen plus an
SEO content specialist I created the
same way. So here comes the most
exciting part is watching them working
together. But before we do that, Clot
needs to know when and who to delegate
it to. So remember the clock empty file
we created in the very first step. So
the key here is to ask claw to review
all the agents in this workspace and
then update that clock.md file with the
agent routing rules. So these are the
instructions that tell claw which agent
to call for different tasks and what are
the trigger phrase and this is an
important step to make the whole system
work. So now it has add these routing
rules that define when it should
delegate to this agent and it even add a
section for the multi- aent workflow
which is amazing and let's test it with
a multi- aent workflow. So we will ask
it to do content research about a
content topic and then create a blog
post and also a presentation deck based
on this content research findings. And
that means both the blog writing and
presentation task will depend on the
first task of content research. So you
can see it start with the first task and
cause the content strategist agent to do
the research through the web search. So
once the task has been complete, it now
move on to the next task for the blog
post creation and dedicate to our SEO
content specialist and the agent now
triggers the keyword research skills
that cause the HFS MCP and then it also
triggers the block writing and document
skills for the actual blog content
creation. Now it move on to the client
presentation task and calls the
presentation agent which will use the
PowerPoint creation skills. So all the
tasks have been done and claw is just
like your team lead give you the summary
for all the deliverables and the agents
that it use. So first the content brief
about the topic backed by research that
is really detailed and follows the
predefined format which is a great
starting point and then the blog post is
pretty impressive as well. So following
all the required formats to make it AI
search friendly, use of bullet points,
FAQ sections and I particularly like
this section about the 10 common pricing
mistake which is great for AI search
engines and what is amazing is I can see
this blog is following the content brief
done by the other agent the content
structure talking points and has almost
5,000 words and you can further enhance
it perhaps also like claw to upload for
you to your final CMS platform and if
you want any of your blog documents to
match your branding and formatting. You
can always create custom branded skills
that use your branded template like how
we did just now. And for the deck is
also using our branded theme. So
everything is on brand and the content
is also using the same content research
findings. So basically all the
deliverables are coherent and aligned to
deliver the same story and this is the
true AI orchestration in action. And now
we have different Asians to achieve a
big task and execute agentic workflows
like this. All right, there are still so
many possibilities and use cases with
Plco. If there are any other topics I
should cover more, let me know in the
comments. And if you enjoy this video,
please also give me a thumbs up. I also
invite you to join our community. Every
month we have deep dive workshop and you
will unlock all the prom resources I
share on this channel, including this
one. I hope to see you there. And before
you go, also watch this video about
clock skills and learn how to apply them
in designing your clock agents and
system. I will see you next time.