You probably already know that Claude
Code is by far the best coding agent in
the world. It can create entire apps
from a simple prompt both front end and
backend. It can blow your mind in terms
of the design of that app. But what you
might not know is you can actually use
Claude Code as a general agent. And
Anthropic released something really
interesting a few weeks ago. they
released what is called Claude skills
which is just a special type of markdown
file which allows you to surround claude
code with relevant skills. So if you
wished that you had an AI agent that had
relevant skills, I believe that this is
probably the most important thing that
you could be studying right now. And so
in this video, we're going to talk about
how to set up Claude skills. We're also
going to talk about how to use Claude
code as a general agent. And we're going
to talk about how you need to set up
your skill.md file and what folders. And
I'm going to show you how to just use AI
to create these skills. Let's talk about
building a general agent with relevant
skills for your business. Whether you're
a content creator, business owner,
aspiring entrepreneur, we're going to
build an agent with relevant skills to
you and we're going to use that agent.
Let's dive in. Okay. So, we're going to
start off by talking about what is a
coding agent. You may have heard of
lovable and this video is not about
lovable. We're not even going to use
lovable. I just wanted to make a point
real quick. So many people are talking
about vibe coding. You can use tools
like lovable, replet, vibe code. These
are coding agents that you can use to
build apps. And whenever I go to lovable
and type in uh make a landing
landing page about pizza
right now, what it's doing is it's
spinning up a sandbox which is basically
a virtual computer and it's going to run
an AI agent or an AI coding agent on the
side. Now, it's going to generate a
bunch of files within a directory or
codebase, and those files are going to
make an app. And so, this is an AI
coding agent at work building an app.
Okay, so it's done. The lovable coding
agent took my prompt, make a landing
page about pizza. It generated all of
the files. This coding agent decided
what files it needed to generate. it
generated them and then it probably
reviewed those files and then it ran the
program in a virtual computer somewhere
so I can see it on my uh browser because
this is within a web browser and so this
is an example of an agent made
specifically for creating simple
applications a very narrow agent
experience where it's made specifically
for creating certain types of apps with
certain stacks and we could do this same
thing on our computer, right? We could
do the same thing on our computer. If we
were to go to Finder, we can just go
straight into our downloads, right? We
can go straight into our downloads and
we could go new folder. We can go like
this. We can say using quad code, right?
So, we don't even need any IDE or
something like cursor or lovable. I can
open a terminal window. I can open a new
terminal at this folder and we can just
run claude. So now we're running claude
code in this empty folder called using
claude code which is an empty folder and
I can just say please build a beautiful
amazing landing page for my pizza shop
Riley's Pizza Shop. Make it in the style
of neo brutalism mixed with a friendly
pizza energy. So just like lovable, we
can run this and claude code in this
empty folder is going to create the
application right here. Okay, check this
out. It just generated an index.html
file. And there we go. It created a file
the same way that Lovable is creating
all the different files and putting them
in a folder in some virtual machine.
It's just a virtual computer. We're
doing this on our computer. It's doing
the same exact thing Lovable is doing.
And the point I want to make here, you
can just use these coding models on your
computer and coding files, right? This
is an HTML file and this is a CSS file.
This is not the only type of file you
can create with cloud code. You can
create any type of file. So it is done.
And if we just copy this link right here
and we paste in localhost80,
we can run this on our computer. This is
running locally on our computer. where
Lovable in Lovable's case, it just
created a virtual machine and it ran it
on that computer and it showed you what
it created on the browser. Now, we're
running this fully on our computer and
we didn't use any like software in
between. We generated the code files
with an AI coding agent on our computer.
It used an AI model from anthropic
servers to create those files. So that's
where it costs money, but we didn't use
any other software other than getting
Claude to generate all the files. And
we're running it on our MacBook Pro. And
this is the website that it created. And
you'll notice that in my opinion, I've
tested every single one of these coding
agents. Just raw Claude code is the best
in the world. So Replet and lovable,
they have their own coding agents.
Claude Code out of the box is better
than all of them. And so what I want to
explain now is how you can use this as a
general agent. So this right here is
Obsidian. And this is just a basic notes
app where every file instead of the
files uh being an HTML file or a
JavaScript file or a CSS file which
ultimately created this uh application
that we can use. Instead of it being one
of those types of files, these are all
markdown files. So the way that I use
general agents is I actually use claude
code at the same location as my notes
like this is my agent workspace. This is
kind of how I think about this. This is
a notebook and Riley Brown uses this as
his personal notebook so that he can be
a better CMO and co-founder of the Vibe
Code app. And I basically state all of
my goals. Why am I stating this? I I
know my goals. Why am I writing this?
because I don't use this by myself. I
use this with my general agent which is
Claude Code. And what I can do here is I
can actually click on this or I can
rightclick on this and hit reveal in
Finder. So here we can see Riley content
creation. That's basically what I called
this file. And you'll see here all of
these different files here. Um like this
is just a wrapper of these files that
are showing up on my computer, right?
This is just in my computer. And so the
same way that I ran claude code in a new
folder, I can run claude code in this
folder. So I can reveal this in finder.
What I'm going to do is I'm going to
rightclick services, new terminal at
folder, right? New terminal at folder.
Now you can see here that it is running.
So we're in this folder right here,
which is the same folder where all of
this is located. And now we can run uh
claude. And so now we have cloud code
running in the folder that has all of my
notes. And so I can use it with cloud
code. So I could go into tasks, right?
And and this is how I keep track of my
tasks. I could go into Q. Um let's say
these are both done, right? This is
these are the things that I want to do.
Um and so in my queue, one thing that I
do want to do, and I can just drag this
in here. One thing that I do want to do
is I want to explain Claude skills to my
audience and make a video. Right? This
is one thing I really want to do. Um I
want to um share the file structure um
with of Claude skills. And then I want
to take my notebook and examine what
Claude skills would be useful for me to
create. And I'm I'm uh do this on this
page. Don't create or edit any other
files. Just make a plan and do it. Okay.
So, we just created this markdown file
of this thing that I want to do. The
cool thing is I can just ask Claude Code
to do it. I can just say, "Do what's in
my queue." Right? That's all I need to
say. I can say, "Yo, do what's in my
queue." And because the first thing that
this agent's going to do is analyze the
readme file. It's going to see how it's
organized, right? It's going to know
that there's tasks. It's going to know
what the queue is, draft tasks. So, it's
just going to know to check the queue.
And because Claude Code is such a
powerful agent and it's really good at
looking through the code base, in this
case, which is just a bunch of my notes,
it's going to find the right location.
It's really smart. And it's going to
find this page, and it's just going to
do what I want it to do. And we'll just
wait for Cloud Code to do that. And
you'll see here that we never said to
look at this file. It doesn't know that
I have this file open. It just found
what's in my queue. And you can see here
it's examining notebook for skill ideas.
It found the right file and now it's
creating the relevant things. Allow it
to edit this session. Boom. Look at
that. So, it just added all of this. It
added all of this
to this document. It told us what skills
are, right? And it told us that uh from
the anthropic skills repo, it it
basically did research. It found uh the
clawed skills repo. And now it is
telling us that you can create within
the claude.md file. You can create a
skill by creating a folder with the
skill name. And inside that folder, it
needs to have a claude or a skill.md
file. And then you can put optional uh
resources within that folder. And so you
can even put assets, references, etc.
And I'll get to that in just a second.
The point I wanted to make is the same
way lovable was a coding specific
example of using an agent. This is a
notes specific example for using an
agent. So I promise you we are we're
working our way up to creating claude
skills. I just wanted to illustrate the
point. I wanted to talk about what a
domain specific agent was like the
lovable agent that can create apps. Then
I showed you a note takingaking example
where you can use claude code as a
general agent. Now, we're going to use
it in a wide openen world within cursor.
And we can do literally whatever we
want. I like to use cursor because it's
just the best in my opinion for quickly
using claude code. And it's ironic
because I use we can just say claude
code skills. So, what uh we're going to
be creating claude skills in this
project. So, I'll just name it that. And
now it is opening up this directory in
an IDE. So cloud uh a cursor is just an
IDE like VS Code where you can view all
the files. And so the way that I vibe
code is I'm just going to come in here
and the first thing that I'm going to do
is hit command J. We're going to open up
the terminal and we're going to type
claude. Then we're going to press this
right here to open up the side panel.
And so now we have Claude code on the
left or on the right. controlling this
directory which is claude code skills
and what we're going to do here is I'm
going to say please take a look at this
direct or at this repo and I'm going to
paste this GitHub uh to the anthropic
skills right here please create one
simple skill in the right format so that
you will use this skill when you need
to. Okay. So, right now it's creating an
example skill. What it's going to do is
it's going to create a cloud file. It's
going to create a cloud file. As you can
see here, it's created this.cloud file.
It's also going to create a skills
folder as you'll see in just a second.
Okay, there you go. It created a folder
called.cloud
and then it created a skills folder
within that. And then it has other
folders beneath it. So it created this
summarized folder with a skill MD.
That's all you need to create a skill.
You just need to put in the docloud
folder because cloud code knows to look
in thecloud folder for certain things
like sub aents and now skills. We're not
talking about sub aents in this video.
We're just talking about skills. So we
created the skills folder. And within
this folder, right, we see this
skill.md.
And every single skill.mmd file should
be formatted with the name and
description. Right? It should have a
name and description. You can see here
that this one that I've created is
called brand voice, which is skill
number one. And then there is a name and
description. And so the name is just a
human-friendly title. It can be
anything. But the crucial part is this
description because it tells Claude code
when to use this skill. And so we're
reaching a point where you can get
agents to do things with a simple
markdown file. But what you need to do
is you need to make sure that you format
it correctly so Cloud Code knows when to
follow your instructions. Because
basically all skills are the way that I
think about them is they are just SOPs
or standard operating procedures. SOPs
for agents. And so right these are
instructions on what to do in certain
scenarios. And if you put a high quality
description, it'll know what instruction
manual or SOP to use when it needs to do
a specific task. And so I don't really
want to use this summarize skill. I
actually want to create a skill that's
much more relevant to me. Okay. So I
just want to show you what I've been
doing. I've been annotating. I've been
annotating my Twitter posts because I
can give these to Claude. I can put
these in Claude skills so that the agent
knows how I post. And so I can say short
video attached to this photo. This is a
Twitter account that I run by the way
that helps me grow Vibe Code. And I can
say um uh senior vibe coder
is ragebait
and works. I don't do this often, right?
Okay. And I just put this directly on
the image. And it helps me kind of
annotate my images here. And I'm just
going to hit I'm just going to exit out.
Hit save. And we can save all these. And
so what we can do here is we can just
take all of these files. We can drag
them in here. And what I'm going to do
is I'm just going to put a new skill
here. And what we can do is we can just
drag these images in here. Now we're
going to go to cloud code. I want you to
replace this uh summarize skill. And
because this is a folder, right? Uh I
can just type at summarize, right? I can
say replace this summarize skill. Uh
this skill, the whole summarize skill uh
should be replaced with a Twitter post X
post skill. This skill should allow the
agent to create tweets in my style and
use the images that are in the at new in
the new skill here folder as a
reference. So please create that skill
now. So we're basically going to tell
cloud code to analyze these images. It's
going to look for patterns in how I
speak. And actually one thing I can
mention, I just hit the backspace.
Just know the red text in these images
are annotations. So that's not part of
the post. These are my annotations to
you on why I did certain things. So take
that into consideration when
constructing this skill, right? So I
annotated why I did what I did. So this
gives some extra context to Cloud Code
and it's going to packages it package it
as a skill. And so in theory whenever I
ask for a Twitter post to claude code in
the future uh within this repo it should
be able to do it in my style because
I've given it relevant context. Okay. So
there you go. It created this skill.md
file and all it did was analyze all of
those images. It converted them into
these uh markdown formats and it
converted it into a skill. What it
didn't do is I didn't specify this. Uh
that was just a temporary folder. Please
remove that folder, but add those images
into that skill folder as references
because this doesn't need to be here.
This can just go into the skill and
right. So right now we have two skills.
We're going to add another skill in just
a second. So we have one skill and every
skill needs a claw.md file. So it just
created this and now it has these
references that it can use right here.
What we can do if we want references
uh to posts
and we can select all of these and we
can just like move them in here.
So we have references and then the
skill.md file. You need this skill.md
file, right? And so what we can do, I
want you to create a markdown file in
the root. And when I say in the root, I
mean right there's the the folder that
we opened up originally which is claude
code skills. This is the root folder. So
it should put it in below thecloud
folder. The dotcloud folder is also in
the root. The skills folder is in the
do.cloud folder. Thus not in the root.
Just wanted to be clear. uh in the root
and come up with 10
ideas for the Twitter copy based on my
last video where I explained Claude
skills
should match and then I can uh give it
that GitHub repo link I mentioned skills
and explained why it's important.
important for general use cases for like
marketing
and as general agent. Okay. So, let's
say I made this video because I'm making
this video right now. What I would
probably do is feed in the transcript of
this video and then it would generate 10
options. So, it would have more context
of the video we're creating. But since
I'm making the video right now, I can't
give it the transcript. Um, but that's
okay. It's going to create a markdown
file in the root and it's going to use
this skill. Okay, so it is done. Okay,
you'll see that when you see this green
dot and it shows expost right here. When
you see this green dot and it has
expost, that means it's using that
skill, right? It is using the expost
skill.
And we're going to allow it to create
these files. And boom, Twitter ideas.
So, here we go. Cloud Code just became a
general agent, not a chatbot, an agent
that does your workflows. Enthropic just
released skills, reusable prompt
templates, invoke with slash commands,
marketing teams. Okay, so this is really
good. Oh my, this shouldn't be possible.
I turned Claude into my personal
marketing team. Social media copy on
demand, email sequences in seconds,
brand voice locked in permanently. Zero
prompting every time. How Claude skills
one markdown file infinite workflows.
This is very good. So it wrote this in
my voice using this skill. But it gets
much cooler than this. So if we were to
go to um let's go to arc. So we're going
to go to typefully.com. And in typefully
we can go to settings and we could go to
API and we can hit new API key. And so
this is going to be test key
for me. Create API key. I'm going to
delete this right after this video. And
then what I'm going to do is I'm going
to click on this docs. And this explains
exactly how to use this API key. So,
what I'm trying to do here is I don't
want it to just come up with ideas. I
want them to draft them in this tool
where I can post directly to social
media. So, in theory, I could have an
agent uh come up with tweets uh and
automatically
draft them within Titefully because
that's what you can do here on this
platform, right? We could have it
directly post this as a um a draft here,
right? It can schedule a new draft. And
so, that's exactly what I'm going to
tell it. So I want you to add to our
x post skill. I'm using the software
typley and I want you to instead of
basically instead of putting these in a
document, I want you to actually
directly schedule these as a draft on
tightfully. And so I am going to give it
these docs to the API. Here are the docs
to read. Here is my API key. It is in a
text file, right? So I don't want to
expose it. What I'm going to do is I'm
just going to go I'm going to go key.txt
txt. I'm going to paste my key right
here. So, I pasted my key in this file
and I can just go at key.txt.
It is here. Please add to the skill
using claude skills. And I'm going to
mention this link right here. Please
make this skill such that it schedules
it as a draft to this typefully account.
It should not post or schedule. Okay,
now we're going to wait for the skill
called expost to be uh messed with.
Okay, so it is done. And here we can see
that your accounts available is Riley
Brown vibe code vibe coding explained.
Okay, so this works. Maybe maybe uh
please test this by um drafting
one of the items in the list
that we generated in and then we can
just go claude skills Twitter ideas.
Okay. Okay. It looks like it is done. If
we come back here. Okay. It created
this, right? It created this on vibe
coding explained. Okay. Now on the Riley
Brown account, draft a post that says,
"Hi, this is a test." Okay, so it's
done. If we go back to Arc, we go to
Riley.
Here we go. We see, "Hi, this is a test.
This was 34 seconds ago." So that's
pretty cool. We can have it draft posts.
I'm going to just reset the context
here. Um, so we're opening up a new
cloud instance to reset it, right? We're
resetting it uh so that there's no
context in here. And I'm going to say, I
just created a tightfully
video that explains how I created a
Claude code skill in order to uh post on
all my Twitter accounts via Typefully. I
want you to draft up three exposts and
draft them on Typefully on the Vibe
Coding Explained account. Oops, I
misspelled it. Typefully
is the app.
Okay, so we interrupted it, but it was
using the Expost skill. It should go
back to using the Expost skill. Okay, do
I want to proceed? Yes. Okay, so the
drafts were created. Oo, it has a link
associated with it. Wait, what happens
if we just go to this link? Wow,
skills repo. It even included that repo.
No way. You can build custom skills for
cloud code, automate repetitive
workflows, create one-click commands,
share skills across projects. Zero
coding required. Just dropped a full
walkth through how to do this. Wow.
Okay, so it created these posts using
the typefully or the expost skill and in
this skill.md file, it has access to
this code, right? You can it has this
code that I can that the claude code can
use to post this on social media. And
what I need to do now is I need to
delete my API key because I probably
exposed it. All right, so there you go.
We just created a general agent and we
gave it a skill. And you know what? I
think that's enough for you to get
started. I don't want to like go crazy
and create like an agent swarm or an
agent with a ton of different skills,
but we just created a we used claude
within cursor to create an agent. And
then we just created one simple skill.
And this is enough for you to get
started because as you saw, I just gave
it the link which I'll put in the
description to the Claude code skills.
So claude code can make your skills for
you and remember you just create you
know you have the root folder right and
then within your project you just have
aclad pro uh folder then you have
another folder uh which is your skills
folder and then within that you just
have the skill name. So this is just
skill uh skill-1 folder and then in here
you have a uh a skill
md file and within that file it will
have a name and description and cloud
code will do that for you. Just make
sure that when you create these skills
right because you can create many of
these. You can create skill one which we
did um and we didn't create more than
one skill right you can create as many
skills as you want. I wouldn't go
overboard, but if you want to create a
general purpose agent and use Cloud
Code, this is how you can do it. And you
can create a bunch of different skills.
And so, in the description down below
this video, you'll find a link to a
webinar. I'm just going to do like a big
live stream where we're going to create
a really cool uh agent interface with a
ton of different skills. We're going to
do it live. It's going to be like 3 to
four hours long. And so, if you want to
sign up for that, that's in the
description. It's going to be sick. But
uh yeah, this is just part two of my
general agent series. I made part one on
Obsidian and I'm just going to continue
this because I'm becoming much more
interested in creating agents with
skills. And in the future, we're going
to mix agent skills with also apps.
We're going to create a little interface
where we can alternate between using an
app that we create and the agent and we
can create things that both me and the
agent can use. It's going to be like an
agent interface or an agent workspace.
And that's what we're going to talk
about in the next video. Uh so thank you
guys for watching.